<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) 2005-2010, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
  <meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8" />
  <title>WSO2 BRS - System Administration Guide</title>
  <link href="css/brs-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" />
  <link href="styles/dist-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css"
  media="all" />
</head>

<body>
<h2>WSO2 BRS - System Administration Guide </h2>

<h4>Contents </h4>

<p>1.0 Introduction<br />
2.0 Document Conventions<br />
3.0 Getting WSO2 BRS<br />
4.0 Installing and Running WSO2 BRS<br />
4.1 Running the BRS in Standalone Mode<br />
4.2 Running BRS Samples<br />
6.0 Using the WSO2 BRS Management Console<br />
7.0 User Management<br />
8.0 Setting Up Logging<br />
9.0 Configuring the Underlying Axis2 Engine<br />
10.0 Adding External Dependencies to the System<br />
11.0 Registry Integration<br />
11.1 Using the Embedded Registry<br />
11.2 Using a Remote Registry<br />
12.0 Setting Up Key Stores<br />
13.0 Setting Up Host Names and Ports<br />
</p>

<h4>1.0 Introduction </h4>

<p>WSO2 BRS is an open source BRS solution.It is to be your Business Rule
Management System (BRMS). Our ultimate goal is to provide you with the suitable
capability of defining, deploying, monitoring, and maintaining your
organization's decisions.</p>

<p>WSO2 BRS supports exposing business decisions as secure and reliable web
services and integrating business decisions to the organizations’ application
integration infrastructure (i.e ESB). </p>

<p>Starting from version 2.0, WSO2 BRS is based on the revolutionary WSO2
Carbon framework. WSO2 Carbon is an OSGi based middleware framework for SOA.
Currently all WSO2 Java products are based on WSO2 Carbon including WSO2
Governance Registry and WSO2 WSAS. Since BRS is OSGi based some knowledge in
OSGi would be helpful in administrating the WSO2 BRS. </p>

<p>This document explains how to get WSO2 BRS and install it on a server. The
latter sections of the document illustrates how to setup and configure various
features of the WSO2 BRS. </p>

<h4>2.0 Document Conventions </h4>
<ul>
  <li>The phrase 'BRS_HOME' refers to the directory in the file system where
    WSO2 BRS is installed</li>
  <li>The phrase 'BRS_SRC_HOME' refers to the directory in the file system
    where WSO2 BRS source distribution is installed</li>
  <li>All file paths follow Unix/Linux conventions but they resemble Windows
    file paths as well</li>
</ul>

<h4>3.0 Getting WSO2 BRS </h4>

<p>Binary distributions and source distributions of WSO2 BRS can be downloaded
free from the <a href="http://wso2.com/products/business-rules-server/">WSO2 BRS project</a> home
page in the <a href="http://wso2.org">WSO2 Oxygen Tank</a>. Before proceeding
to the downloads page you will be asked to register on the WSO2 Oxygen Tank.
Registration is free and optional however it is recommended that you sign up
for an account right away since registered Oxygen Tank users get exclusive
access to our support forums and tons of valuable content related to SOA and
Web Services. </p>

<p>Once you are on the downloads page click on the relevant links to download a
binary distribution or a source distribution of the latest stable release of
the WSO2 BRS. If you are interested in an older version of the BRS, scroll down
in the downloads page to locate the links to previous releases. You will also
find links to download developer releases and nightly builds of the WSO2 BRS on
the same page. We recommend that you always download the latest stable release.
If you want to try out a feature that was added very recently you can try out a
nightly build. </p>

<p>If you downloaded a source distribution of the BRS you need to build the
source to get the executable binary. WSO2 BRS uses an <a
href="http://maven.apache.org">Apache Maven2</a> based build system and
therefore you need to first download and install Apache Maven2. Please refer
Maven2 documentation on installing and configuring Apache Maven2. Also note
that Apache Maven2 requires Java to run. Once Maven2 is properly configured
extract the downloaded source distribution and change your working directory to
the directory that is created. Then execute the command mvn clean install to
run the builder. Once the build process is complete you can find the binary
distribution archive in BRS_SRC_HOME/modules/distribution/target directory. </p>

<h4>4.0 Installing and Running WSO2 BRS </h4>

<p>To install the WSO2 BRS simply extract the downloaded binary distribution
archive. If you built WSO2 BRS from source extract the archive created by the
builder. We recommend installing WSO2 BRS on a Unix/Linux system since that
will enable you to get the maximum out of the BRS. In order to be able to start
WSO2 BRS you first need Java 5 or higher. Having installed Java on your system
please set the JAVA_HOME environment variable to point to the directory in
which Java is installed. </p>

<h5>4.1 Running WSO2 BRS in Standalone Mode </h5>

<p>Now you are all set to start WSO2 BRS in the standalone mode. Go to
BRS_HOME/bin directory and if you are on Unix/Linux execute the wso2server.sh
shell script or if you are on Windows execute the wso2server.bat batch file.
This will start the BRS and you can see the progress of the startup procedure
on the console. Please note that server startup may take some time depending on
the hardware configuration of your system. The first time startup can take up
few additional seconds since some first time configuration logic is run by the
BRS. If the server started up cleanly you should get an output similar to the
following on the console. </p>
<pre>[2010-03-08 13:04:00,953]  INFO - Main Initializing system...
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Starting WSO2 Carbon...
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Operating System : Windows XP 5.1, x86
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Java Home        : C:\Program Files\Java\jdk1.6.0_14\jre
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Java Version     : 1.6.0_14
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Java VM          : Java HotSpot(TM) Client VM 14.0-b16,Sun Microsystems Inc.
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Carbon Home      : C:\Project\wso2-new\carbon\trucnk\products\brs\modules\DISTRI~1\target\WSO2BR~2.0-S\bin\..
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator Java Temp Dir    : C:\Project\wso2-new\carbon\trucnk\products\brs\modules\DISTRI~1\target\WSO2BR~2.0-S\bin\..\tmp
[2010-03-08 13:04:07,140]  INFO - CarbonCoreActivator User             : indika kumara, en-US, Asia/Colombo
[2010-03-08 13:04:09,078]  INFO - RegistryCoreServiceComponent Registry Mode    : READ-WRITE
[2010-03-08 13:04:10,546]  INFO - CarbonServerManager Starting Carbon initialization...
[2010-03-08 13:04:10,796]  INFO - ClusterBuilder Clustering has been disabled
[2010-03-08 13:04:10,875]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : wso2xfer-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:10,937]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : sandesha2-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,062]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : rampart-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,062]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : rahas-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,093]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : wso2mex-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,234]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : wso2caching-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,250]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : wso2throttle-SNAPSHOT
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,343]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 module : addressing-1.5
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,343]  INFO - ModuleDeployer Deploying module: addressing-1.5 - file:/C:/Project/wso2-new/carbon/trucnk/products/brs/modules/DISTRI~1/target/WSO2BR~2.0-S/bin/../repository/deployment/server/axis2modules/addressing-1.5.
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,375]  INFO - ModuleDeployer Deploying module: metadataExchange - file:/C:/Project/wso2-new/carbon/trucnk/products/brs/modules/distribution/target/wso2brs-1.2.0/lib/mex-SNAPSHOT-impl.jar
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,562]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 service : echo
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,656]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: echo - file:/C:/Project/wso2-new/carbon/trucnk/products/brs/modules/DISTRI~1/target/WSO2BR~2.0-S/bin/../repository/deployment/server/axis2services/echo/
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,796]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 service : version
[2010-03-08 13:04:11,828]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: version - file:/C:/Project/wso2-new/carbon/trucnk/products/brs/modules/DISTRI~1/target/WSO2BR~2.0-S/bin/../repository/deployment/server/axis2services/version/
[2010-03-08 13:04:12,218]  INFO - ModuleDeployer Deploying module: addressing-1.5 - file:/C:/Project/wso2-new/carbon/trucnk/products/brs/modules/DISTRI~1/target/WSO2BR~2.0-S/bin/../repository/deployment/client/modules/addressing-1.5.mar
[2010-03-08 13:04:12,234]  INFO - ModuleDeployer Deploying module: metadataExchange - file:/C:/Project/wso2-new/carbon/trucnk/products/brs/modules/distribution/target/wso2brs-1.2.0/lib/mex-SNAPSHOT-impl.jar
[2010-03-08 13:04:12,875]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: org.wso2.carbon.identity.authenticator.token - {1}
[2010-03-08 13:04:12,921]  WARN - DefaultSchemaGenerator We don't support method overloading. Ignoring [getLogs]
[2010-03-08 13:04:13,906]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 service : wso2carbon-sts
[2010-03-08 13:04:13,937]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: org.wso2.carbon.sts - {1}
[2010-03-08 13:04:14,312]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: org.wso2.carbon.tryit - {1}
[2010-03-08 13:04:14,625]  INFO - DeploymentInterceptor Deploying Axis2 service : XKMS
[2010-03-08 13:04:14,703]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: org.wso2.carbon.xkms - {1}
[2010-03-08 13:04:14,718]  INFO - DeploymentEngine Deploying Web service: org.wso2.carbon.xkms.mgt - {1}
[2010-03-08 13:04:14,828]  INFO - CarbonServerManager Repository       : C:\Project\wso2-new\carbon\trucnk\products\brs\modules\DISTRI~1\target\WSO2BR~2.0-S\bin\..\repository\deployment\server/
[2010-03-08 13:04:15,328]  INFO - HttpsTransportListener HTTPS port       : 9443
[2010-03-08 13:04:15,328]  INFO - HttpTransportListener HTTP port        : 9763
[2010-03-08 13:04:16,796]  INFO - CarbonUIServiceComponent Mgt Console URL  : https://10.100.1.100:9443/carbon/
[2010-03-08 13:04:16,796]  INFO - StartupFinalizerServiceComponent Started Transport Listener Manager
[2010-03-08 13:04:16,796]  INFO - StartupFinalizerServiceComponent Server           :  WSO2 BRS-1.2.0
[2010-03-08 13:04:16,796]  INFO - StartupFinalizerServiceComponent WSO2 Carbon started in 15 sec

</pre>

<p>To verify that the BRS is up and running fire off your Web browser and go to
https://localhost:9443/carbon. This will take you to the WSO2 BRS on-line
management console. </p>
<img src="images/login.PNG" alt="Log-in" /> 

<p>You can login to the console using the default user credentials given below.
</p>
<ul>
  <li>Username: admin</li>
  <li>Password: admin</li>
</ul>

<p>If you can get that far then the BRS is properly installed and running. </p>

<p>WSO2 BRS startup scripts stated above accept a few useful arguments. </p>

<p>--cleanRegistry<br />
  This argument forces the embedded Registry instance to be cleaned before
starting the BRS. Note that this will clean the internal database therefore any
configurations you saved previously will be permanently lost. </p>

<p>--restart<br />
   Restart the Carbon Unix daemon.</p>

<p>-debug &lt;port&gt;<br />
   Enables remote debugging on the BRS through the specified port. </p>

<p>-dump<br />
   Print a thread dump of the Carbon Unix daemon.</p>


<p>In addition to the above mentioned arguments the BRS startup scripts accept
the following VM arguments. </p>

<p>-DosgiConsole<br />
   Starts the OSGi console from which you can directly interact with the
underlying OSGi runtime. </p>

<h4>4.2 Running BRS Samples </h4>

<p>WSO2 BRS ships with a set of sample configurations which enables you to get
familiar with the product quickly and easily. Please refer the WSO2 BRS samples
guide for sample configuration and details on how to run them. </p>

<h4>5.0 WSO2 BRS Directory Hierarchy </h4>

<p>When you extract a WSO2 BRS binary distribution archive you will find the
following directories in the top level that is created. </p>

<p>bin -<br />
Contains all the necessary scripts to interact with the WSO2 BRS instance.
There are shell scripts (with .sh extension) for Unix/Linux users and batch
files (with .bat extension) for Windows users. In general you will find the
following scripts in this directory.<br />
<br />
<ul>
  <li>wso2server.sh/wso2server.bat - Launches WSO2 BRS </li>
  <li>wsdl2java.sh/wsdl2java.bat - Launches the Java stub generation tool for
    Web Services </li>
  <li>java2wsdl.sh/java2wsdl.bat - Launches the WSDL generation tool for Java
    Web Services </li>
  <li>tcpmon.sh/tcpmon.bat - Launches TCPMon, the TCP connection monitor </li>
  <li>chpasswd.sh/chpasswd.bat -Use this script to change the administrator
    password without signing in to the server<br />
  </li>
  <li>daemon.sh -Start WSO2 BRS as a daemon on Unix/Linux systems<br />
  </li>
  <li>install.bat - Install WSO2 BRS as a background service on Windows<br />
  </li>
  <li>repowriter.sh/repowriter.bat </li>
</ul>
<br />
In addition to the above mentioned scripts you will find a sub-directory named
'native' in the bin directory.<br />
</p>

<p>repository/deployment -<br />
This directory houses all the OSGi bundles, service artifacts, modules and
related resources used by the WSO2 BRS instance. The repository/components/plugins 
directory will contain all the necessary OSGi bundles at server runtime.</p>

<p>repository/conf -<br />
All the global configuration files (eg: axis2.xml, transports-mgt.xml,
carbon.xml , rule-component.conf) used by the BRS are stored in this directory.
</p>

<p>lib -<br />
The lib directory houses all the jar files and OSGi bundles required by the
embedded Tomcat instance. Starting from Carbon 2.0 the log4j.properties file
used by the BRS is also stored here. </p>

<p>resources -<br />
Contains additional resources required by WSO2 BRS. This includes security
related resources such as keystores. </p>

<p>repository/logs -<br />
All the server logs created during server runtime will be stored here. </p>

<p>dbscripts -<br />
Contains a collection of database scripts required to create the Carbon
database on a variety of database management systems.<br />
</p>

<h4>6.0 Using the WSO2 BRS Management Console </h4>

<p>WSO2 BRS management console is a Web based control panel powered by JSP and
AJAX which enables system administrators to interact with a running BRS
instance, without having to touch any underlying configuration files. The
management console allows the users to command and control proxy services,
sequences, transports, local entries, registry, modules, endpoints and much
more. BRS management console is a great way to try things out without having to
edit the actual configuration files or without having to restart the BRS for
changes to take effect. </p>

<p>We recommend using Mozilla Firefox 3 or Internet Explorer 7 to access the
WSO2 BRS management console. Please note that your browser must be JavaScript
enabled to take the full advantage of the management console. To access the BRS
management console fire off you Web browser and navigate to https://&lt;Server
Host&gt;:&lt;Server Port&gt;/&lt;Context&gt;. If you are running the Web
browser on the same machine as the BRS you may use 'localhost' as the server
host. The default port and the context for the BRS management console are
'9443' and 'carbon' respectively. If you entered the URL correctly you will be
taken to the management console's login page. </p>

<p>On the login page enter 'admin' as the username and the password to login to
the system. You can change user credentials and even add new users once you
login. Controls and wizards in the BRS management console are pretty much self
explanatory. However if you are having trouble finishing your way in the
management console, click on the 'Help' link at the top right corner of any
page to access context sensitive help. </p>

<p>Please note that the BRS management console makes use of the default HTTPS
servlet transport which is configured in the BRS_HOME/conf/transports.xml file.
It is important that this transport is always properly configured in the
mentioned file. Otherwise the management console might be inaccessible to the
users. </p>

<h4>7.0 User Management </h4>

<p>To access the WSO2 BRS user management features, first sign in to the BRS
management console and click on 'User Management' under the 'Configure' menu in
the left navigation bar. This will take you to the User Management home page
which contains the controls illustrated below. </p>
<img src="images/user-mgt.PNG" alt="User Mgt" />

<p>From here you can manage users and roles. A user is associated with zero or
more roles (generally specified at user creation time) and each role is
associated with zero or more permissions (generally specified at role creation
time). Therefore the set of permissions owned by a user is determined by the
roles assigned to that user. A user owns the union of all the permissions
associated with the roles assigned to that user. By default BRS comes with only
one role, the 'admin' role. This role is associated with the following set of
permissions. (In fact all the BRS related permissions are listed here, meaning
that users with admin role gets all the permissions over the system) </p>
<ul>
  <li>login </li>
  <li>manage-configuration </li>
  <li>manage-security </li>
  <li>upload-services </li>
  <li>manage-services </li>
  <li>monitor-system </li>
  <li>delegate-identity </li>
</ul>

<p>By default the admin user is associated with the admin role and hence the
admin user is entitled to all the above permissions. </p>

<p>To add a new role to the system click on 'Roles' in the User Management home
page and on the page that appears click the 'Add New Role' link. This will
start the 'Add Role' wizard. The wizard will guide you though the process of
creating a role by specifying a unique name for the role and adding the
relevant permissions to the new role. Similarly to create a new user, click on
'Users' in the User Management home page. Then from the next page that appears
select 'Create New User' link. This will launch the 'Add User' wizard which
will enable you to create a new user account with login credentials and
associate the account with one or more existing roles. The BRS management
console also enables you to search for and modify existing users and roles. </p>

<p>WSO2 BRS can be easily configured to use an external user store in addition
to the built-in system user store. An external user store is an external
database which stores user data. It could be as simple as a relational database
or as sophisticated as an LDAP instance. Most organizations maintain such
centralized databases and it would be productive from the organization's point
of view to have the BRS pick up user data from the existing centralized user
database. To connect the BRS to an external user store simply click on the 'Add
External User Store' link on the User Management home page. Then on the page
that appears select the type of user store that will be plugged into the BRS.
Currently the following types of user stores are supported. </p>
<ul>
  <li>JDBC </li>
  <li>LDAP </li>
  <li>Active Directory </li>
</ul>

<p>Having selected the type of the user store you need to provide additional
information required by the BRS to connect to and retrieve user data from the
external user store. If all the required parameters were specified accurately
the BRS will pick up user data from the external user store and users
registered on the external store will be able to access the BRS as if their
accounts were created in the built-in system user store. </p>

<h4>8.0 Setting Up Logging </h4>

<p>Logging is one of the most important aspects of a production grade server. A
properly configured logging system is vital in identifying errors, security
threats and usage patterns. WSO2 BRS uses a log4j based logging mechanism
through Apache Commons Logging facade library. The log4j.properties file which
governs how logging is performed by the server can be found in BRS_HOME/lib
directory. However it is recommended not to make any alterations to the default
log4j.properties file. The recommended way of setting up logging is by using
the BRS management console. Simply login to the management console and click on
'Logging' under the 'Configure' menu in the left navigation bar. From here you
can setup various appenders and configure log levels for various loggers. Any
changes to the logging configuration you make from the management console will
get priority over what is defined in the actual log4j.properties file. </p>

<p>By default WSO2 BRS comes with the following log appenders configured. </p>
<ul>
  <li>CARBON_CONSOLE (Logs to the console when the server is running) </li>
  <li>CARBON_LOGFILE (Writes the logs to BRS_HOME/logs/wso2-BRS.log) </li>
  <li>CARBON_MEMORY </li>
  <li>CARBON_SYS_LOG </li>
  <li>SERVICE_APPENDER (Writes mediation time audit messages to
    BRS_HOME/logs/wso2-BRS-service.log) </li>
  <li>TRACE_APPENDER (Writes mediation time tracing/debug messages to the
    BRS_HOME/logs/wso2-BRS-trace.log for tracing enabled services) </li>
  <li>TRACE_MEMORYAPPENDER </li>
</ul>

<p>Tracing can be enabled for individual mediation sequences and proxy services
from the 'Mediation Sequences' home page and the 'Service Dashboard' page
respectively. Click on the 'Sequences' link under 'Mediation' in the 'Manage'
menu of the left navigation bar to access the 'Mediation Sequences' page. This
page lists all the deployed sequences. Each sequence gives you the options to
enable/disable tracing. To access the service dashboard for a proxy service go
to the Services List page and click on the proxy service that you are
interested in. Once a sequence or a proxy service is tracing enabled you can
view the generated log messages by visiting the 'Mediation Tracer' page under
the 'Monitor' menu. The 'Monitor' menu also gives you access to the system logs
and the SOAP tracer logs all through the Web interface itself. </p>
<img src="images/logs.PNG" alt="Logs" />
 </body>
</html>
